<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science &amp; Analytics Portfolio on H. Shamil Samsudeen</title>
    <link>https://hshamilsamsudeen.github.io/Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science &amp; Analytics Portfolio on H. Shamil Samsudeen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hshamilsamsudeen.github.io/Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fiera Real Estate: Predictive Modeling for Canadian Real Estate</title>
      <link>https://hshamilsamsudeen.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hshamilsamsudeen.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>This was a Capstone Project which used census data, CBRE data and Python to program a model that can be repeatedly used to help with data backed decision making for real estate investments which aims to minimize the risk associated with high value asset investment.
The regression model developed is able to predict vacancy rates for geographical locations using 6 major variables. These final variables include Total Available Inventory, Availability Rate, Average Asking Sale Price $/sq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safe Roads Competition 2021</title>
      <link>https://hshamilsamsudeen.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hshamilsamsudeen.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-7/</guid>
      <description>This project was a submission in the Safe Roads Competition 2021 hosted by SAS, Geotab and the Toronto Police Services. The objective of this project was to investigate factors that contributes to vehicle collisions with cyclists, and the impact of drivingbehavior and compliance with traffic regulations oncyclist safety.
The data used for this study was from the KSI (Killed or Seriously Injured) dataset provided by the Toronto Police services and additional data from the Geotab Ignition hazardous areas and road impediments dataset were used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association Analysis - Catalog Cross Selling</title>
      <link>https://hshamilsamsudeen.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hshamilsamsudeen.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>This group project required performing an association analysis to develop rules and collaborative filtering. The group acted as a team of analysts for an hypothetical organisation. The team presented the final results in order to help the hypothetical business make an informed decision on which catalog to promote in a direct-mail marketing campaign focused on cross-selling.
Project Files - GitHub Repository link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Children&#39;s Retail Market Analysis</title>
      <link>https://hshamilsamsudeen.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hshamilsamsudeen.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>This project uses the Canadian Census data for the year 2016, which was published by Statistics Canada. In order to understand the children’s retail market, with a mission of helping set up new store locations for businesses.
This analysis would help businesses understand it’s potential consumers in age groups below 20, population distributions for this demography, purchasing power, and potential market growth opportunities.
The key business questions were;
 Selecting the top locations for setting up new childrens retail stores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ontario Museum Association - Market Research</title>
      <link>https://hshamilsamsudeen.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hshamilsamsudeen.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>This primary market research project sought to gain insights and answers from the research question,&amp;ldquo;How does digitalization affect the visitor engagement at museums?&amp;rdquo;
The main purpose was to contribute to the client&amp;rsquo;s (OMA) 2025 digitization strategy for museums in Ontario. Contributions involved developing further insights, supporting and validating assumptions.
This research would help gauge consumer perception about the digitalization of museums and enable us to find opportunities for further improvement &amp;amp; innovation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sri Lanka Immigration - ERD</title>
      <link>https://hshamilsamsudeen.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hshamilsamsudeen.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>This project required creating an Entity Relationship Diagram (ERD) for the Sri Lanka Immigration Department. The ERD was based on an entry visit form, and uses Data Modeling best practices such as Normalization. 1NF, 2NF &amp;amp; 3NF were used when constructing the conceptual and physical relational model design.
Project Files - GitHub Repository link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel Agency - BPM</title>
      <link>https://hshamilsamsudeen.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hshamilsamsudeen.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>This mini project comprised of creating a Business Process Map. Due to my domain knowledge a travel agency was created for this case.
The project focuses on:
 Data which would be needed to be collected to measure the effectiveness of processes. How results would be measured. How process effectiveness and efficiency could be improved.  Project Files - GitHub Repository link   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://hshamilsamsudeen.github.io/Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hshamilsamsudeen.github.io/Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Connect with me on LinkedIn and follow my work on GitHub.
         Location - Toronto, Ontario, Canada   E-Mail - shamil2007@gmail.com              LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/shamil-samsudeen/   GitHub - https://github.com/HShamilSamsudeen    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
